Summary

I am currently a data scientist at IHS Markit. I analyse data from company databases to drive optimization and improvement of product development and business strategies. From 2013 to 2016, I was a research associate at University College London (UCL). I worked on a geospatial big data project called IQmulus which provided a platform to process massive amounts of geospatial data and serve useful knowledge by processing algorithms developed by the project. From 2010 to 2013, I was a Ph.D. researcher at the ALICE team of INRIA (French Institute for Research in Computer Science and Automation). I carried out extensive research which proposed novel methods to process 3D data acquired by multiple cameras. I received my doctorate in computer science from Institut National Polytechnique de Lorraine. Please see my LinkedIn profile https://www.linkedin.com/in/kwunlyou for more information.

Specialities

Machine Learning, Data Analysis, Optimization, Numerical Analysis

Skills & Expertise

Programming Python, C++, Scala

Libraries Apache Spark, Scikit-learn, SuiteSparse, OpenGL, QT

Operating Systems Linux, macOS, Windows

Others Amazon AWS, Git, Jenkins, Docker, Terraform, Ansible

Experience

2018 - Present Data Scientist, IHS Markit, United Kingdom.

As a data scientist, I analyse data from company databases to drive optimization and improvement of product development and business strategies. My daily work is to develop data-driven solutions by means of the cutting edge machine learning technologies.

2016 - 2018 Data Scientist, MediaGamma Ltd, United Kingdom.

I was developing applications for programmatic advertising by applying machine learning technologies. The role is to design and build automatic solutions which address large-scale machine learning problems in computational advertising.

2013 - 2016 **Research associate**, *University College London*, United Kingdom.

I am a contributor to the project IQmulus (http://www.iqmulus.eu/) funded by European Commission. This project aims to create a high-volume fusion and analysis platform for large geospatial datasets. I am developing and implementing methods to process large LiDAR datasets using the state-of-the-art cluster computing engine Apache Spark.

2010 - 2013 **PhD researcher**, *INRIA-Nancy Grand-Est*, France.

I was involved in the project Physigrafix which combines acquisition techniques, geometry, and mechanics to develop simulation models that accurately reproduces realistic deformation. My work aims to develop specialized methods suitable for processing point data originating from multi-view reconstruction.

Education

2010 - 2013 PhD candidate, Computer Science, Institut National Polytechnique de Lorraine.

2008 - 2010 M.S., Applied Mathematics, Zhejiang University.

Excellent Graduation Thesis in Zhejiang University

2004 - 2008 **B.S**, Mathematics, Zhejiang University.

Excellent Graduation Thesis in Zhejiang University

Overall GPA: 3.82/4.0 (87.22/100)

GPA of the last two years: 3.86/4.0 (89.75/100)

Languages

English Professional working proficiency

Mandarin Chinese Native

Honors & Awards

2005 Excellent Undergraduate of the year

2005 Scholarship of State-level Training Base

2007 Scholarship of State-level Training Base

2009 Excellent Graduate Scholarship of the year

Publications

Change Detection of Mobile LiDAR Data using Cloud Computing

Int. Arch. Photogramm. Remote Sens. Spatial Inf. Sci., 2016

Authors: Kun Liu, Jan Boehm, Christian Alis

http://www.int-arch-photogramm-remote-sens-spatial-inf-sci.net/XLI-B3/309/2016/

Classification of Big Point Cloud Data using Cloud Computing

Int. Arch. Photogramm. Remote Sens. Spatial Inf. Sci., XL-3/W3, 553-557, 2015

Authors: Kun Liu, Jan Boehm

http://www.int-arch-photogramm-remote-sens-spatial-inf-sci.net/XL-3-W3/553/2015/

Sphere Packing Aided Surface Reconstruction for Multi-view Data

10th International Symposium on Visual Computing (ISVC), 2014

Authors: Kun Liu, Patricio A. Galindo, Rhaleb Zayer

https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-319-14364-4_17

A New Framework For Interactive Segmentation of Point Clouds

Int. Arch. Photogramm. Remote Sens. Spatial Inf. Sci., XL-5, 357-362, 2014

Authors: Kun Liu, Jan Boehm

http://www.int-arch-photogramm-remote-sens-spatial-inf-sci.net/XL-5/357/2014/

Bundle Adjustment Constrained Smoothing For Multi-View Point Cloud Data

8th International Symposium on Visual Computing (ISVC), 2012

Authors: Kun Liu, Rhaleb Zayer

https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-642-33179-4_13

Paint Mesh Cutting

Computer Graphic Forum (Proceedings of Eurographics 2011)

Authors: Lubin Fan, Ligang Liu, Kun Liu

http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/wol1/doi/10.1111/j.1467-8659.2011.01895.x/full